<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
    <channel>

        <title>Announcements</title>
        <link>http://usiu.aksalj.me/assets/xml/announcements.xml</link>
        <description>Notice board announcements</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 06:37:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>

        <item>
            <title>USIU-Africa Breaks Ground for Ksh. 735 Million Student Center</title>
            <link>http://www.usiu.ac.ke/index/on-campus/news/usiu-africa-breaks-ground-for-ksh-735-million-student-center</link>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://www.usiu.ac.ke/index/images/News/1.jpg"/>
            <description>USIU-Africa broke ground today for the new student center designed to cater to a student population of approximately 8,000 students. The 77,120 square feet building is estimated to cost the institution KShs. 735 Million and will be ready for occupancy in 18 months.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>USIU-Africa broke ground today for the new student center designed to cater to a student population of approximately 8,000 students. The 77,120 square feet building is estimated to cost the institution KShs. 735 Million and will be ready for occupancy in 18 months.</p>

<p>Activities that will be carried out in the building will complement and enhance the overall educational experience of students through development of, exposure to, and participation in social, intellectual, recreational, and governance programs. Offices that will be hosted in the building will include Career and Placement Services, Counselling, Exchange programs offices, academic support services and Student Leadership. The centralization of student services that will be located at the center will help empower students to focus more intensely on their studies and their personal growth.<br /><br />The building will also host a kitchen where students undertaking a Bachelor of Science in Hotel and Restaurant Management will get hands on experience. This ensures that the campus training facility is more accessible as the institution has had to hire training facilities from external establishments in the past. The building will also house a fitness center with the most up to date equipment and an expanded healthcare center.</p>
<p>Based on the nature of activity that will be carried out in the building, security of occupants is essential. Security monitoring systems will therefore been integrated throughout the location with key areas that have access control. Emergency generated power will also be provided for on the premises for safety. The use of high quality solar control, low energy glass and natural ventilation systems will also go a long way in reducing the amount of solar gain in the building. Accessibility for the disabled at the state of the art building will be catered for as the various levels will be vertically connected by lifts as well as ramps.</p>
<p>Speaking at the ceremony, the Vice Chancellor Prof. Freida brown emphasized the importance of Student Affairs and Services in the development of any higher learning institution. “At USIU-Africa, we believe in a well-rounded student which we know the education ministry has stressed in its strategies for improving higher education in Kenya. We are committed to playing our part and today’s ceremony is a sign of our devotion to education in Africa,” said Prof. Brown.</p>
<p>As a not for profit institution of higher learning, USIU-Africa is dependent on tuition and several years of saving has therefore been the source of funds for the development. High interest rates have made borrowing of large sums of money for construction cost prohibitive. “I would encourage the ministry to support the re-establishment of the VAT Exemption on construction that private universities enjoyed during retired President Kibaki’s administration. KShs. 122 Million would have been saved and placed toward additional facilities, books, or scholarships for needy students if the exemption was still available,” stated Prof. Brown.</p>
<p>With the private sector not having access to low interest rate loans or government capitation grants, investment in capital projects in private higher education institutions is expensive. The University Funding Board proposed in the Universities Bill of 2012 if established would therefore go a long way in providing conditional loans and grants to private universities.</p>
<p>With over 45 years of involvement in higher education in Kenya, USIU-Africa is a dual accredited university in Kenya and the United States. This ensures that the institution is focused and engaged on issues of quality assurance not only in areas centered on program development that address societal and market needs but also on facility expansion and investment.</p>
<p>“The Student Center will not only help to differentiate ourselves from other institutions by providing quality education but will also ensure that we meet our responsibility of contributing positively to a well balanced workforce for Africa’s advancement,” said Mrs. Rita Asunda, the Deputy Vice Chancellor for Student Affairs and Enrollment Management.</p>
<p>“Universities must aim at giving graduates relevant curriculum and life skills with the changing times of our rising continent-Africa,” stated the USIU-Africa Chancellor, Dr. Manu Chandaria who was also present at the event.</p>
<p>Representing the Cabinet Secretary for Education, Prof. Henry Moses Thairu the Chairperson of the Commission for University Education in his remarks urged institutions of higher learning to uphold the highest standards of quality education and not to become centers of revenue collection by duping unsuspecting customers seeking an education. Through his delivered speech, Prof. Kaimenyi committed to taking appropriate action against institutions that have allegedly been accused of dubious unethical undertaking such as delivering substandard education through unqualified faculty who lack both the expertise and basic materials to teach and improper upgrading of learners in various public and private institutions of higher learning.</p>

                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
            <author>Zakaria Davis</author>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 06:37:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>

    </channel>
</rss>
