<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
    <channel>

        <title>Press Releases</title>
        <link>http://board.aksalj.me/assets/xml/press.xml</link>
        <description>USIU Press Releases</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 06:37:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>

        <item>
            <title>Science Building Handed Over</title>
            <link>http://www.usiu.ac.ke/index/on-campus/news/science-building-handed-over</link>
            <media:thumbnail url="http://www.usiu.ac.ke/index/images/News/Science_Building_Tour_1.jpg"/>
            <description>The USIU-Africa Science Building Keys were handed over to the Chairman of the board, Dr. Manu Chandaria by the building contractor at a private event held on site on 13th November 2014.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                <p>
                <strong>The USIU-Africa Science Building Keys were handed over to the Chairman of the board, Dr. Manu Chandaria by the building contractor at a private event held on site on 13th November 2014.</strong> <br /><br /> Also present at the event were members of the board, representatives of the management council, Faculty and Staff from the School of Science and Technology as well as members of the Student Association Council. <br /> <br /> In her remarks, the Vice Chancellor Prof. Freida Brown, expressed her confidence that the faculty from the School of Science and Technology would not only continue their commitment in providing high standards of quality education but would also delve deeper into research and patent creation to the benefit of the continent. “This ushers in a new era for USIU-Africa and reemphasizes our commitment to invest in offering of Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics programs which will fundamentally improve the nation’s competitiveness in technology development and in turn transform our society and other parts of Africa through opportunities for new inventions,” said Prof. Brown. <br /><br /><img class="img-responsive" src="/index/images/News/Science_Building_Tour_1.jpg" alt="Science Building Handed Over " /><br /><br /> The 7,500 square feet building whose construction commenced in September 2013 and has cost over KShs. 500 Million will house 8 classrooms, 8 laboratories, 2 lecture theatres, 2 meeting rooms and 28 offices. <br /><br /> As part of USIU-Africa’s drive to be energy efficient and sustainable, part of the design process was to ensure that Building Sustainability Standards were followed as close as possible. Environmentally-friendly features such as hot water solar panels on the roof have been incorporated for kitchen water usage, occupancy censors to ensure saving on power and plumbing fixtures were carefully chosen to minimize the use of water. <br /><br /> Based on the nature of activity that will be carried out in the building, security of occupants was essential. Security monitoring systems have therefore been integrated throughout the location with key areas that have access control. Emergency generated power has also been provided for on the premises for safety. <br /><br /> The use of high quality solar control, low energy glass and natural ventilation systems will also go a long way in reducing the amount of solar gain in the building. <br /><br /> Accessibility for the disabled at the state of the art building has been catered for as the various levels are vertically connected by lifts as well as ramps that are wide enough for the movement of laboratory trollies. <br /><br /> Irrigation of the new landscaping will be done with water that is collected from the new Science building and the library building. The landscape designer also ensured that indigenous tree species that were uprooted to make way for the construction have now been planted around the new building. <br /><br /> The Students Centre whose construction plans are underway will be close to the Science Building. <br /><br /><img class="img-responsive" src="/index/images/News/Science_Building_Tour_2.jpg" alt="Science Building Handed Over " />
                </p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
            <author>Zakaria Davis</author>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 06:37:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>

    </channel>
</rss>
